Imputing values into a data set
向数据集中填充值
is probably the most common way professionals work with missing values.
可能是很多数据科学家处理缺失值的最常用方法
However, it's important to understand its drawbacks.
但是 了解这种方法的缺点也非常重要
First, let's look at some common methods for imputing missing values.
首先 来看一些常见的填充缺失值的方法
These include imputing the mean, the median,
包括使用某一列的均值、
or the mode for any particular column with missing values.
中位数或者众数填充该列的缺失值
We could also just predict missing values using other columns in our dataset.
还可以用其他列的数据来预测某一列的缺失值
This could use any supervised learning approach you're already familiar with,
可以使用任何一种你熟悉的监督学习方法
from linear regression to a tree-based approach.
比如 线性回归或者树模型
Or we could find rows that are most similar in the values that are not
还可以利用行之间相似的特性
missing and then fill the missing values with the values from these rows.
使用其他相似行中的对应值来填充
In this case notice,
这种情况下 需要注意
all of these columns have matching values but here we're missing this point.
所有的列都应该有匹配的特征值 只有此处存在缺失值
So we might fill it with the value that we find for this individual.
所以我们可能需要单独地对某些值进行填充
This is like a k-nearest neighbors approach to filling in missing values.
比较像用 k 近邻算法来填充缺失值
It's important to remember that by imputing these values,
需要注意的是
using any of these methods,
用任何的方法来填充缺失值
you're diluting the importance of the feature.
都会淡化该特征的重要性
Variability in the features is what allows
特征的可变性可以帮助你
you to use them to predict any variable better.
提升模型最后的预测结果
By imputing values, you have the pro and that you are removing data,
通过填充 虽然减少了数据里的缺失值
however you have the con that you're diluting the power of your features to predict well,
但同时也因为降低了特征的可变性
by reducing the variability in those features.
削弱了该特征对预测结果的帮助
As an example, consider you are interested in using age,
举个例子 你想要利用年龄、
a mother's height, and a father's height,
母亲的身高、父亲的身高
to predict a child's height.
来预测孩子的身高
If you don't have a mother or father's height or an age,
如果你没有母亲或者父亲的身高 或者年龄
you could just fill these in with the mean,
可以简单使用每一列的均值、
the median, or the mode for each column.
中位数或者众数来填充
We can take the average for each column and fill the missing ages and heights with
我们可以算出每一列的均值 然后用均值来填充缺失的数据
this calculated value but now we have made
但这样的话
these rows more similar when actually we don't know this to be true.
行之间变得更相似 我们也不知道这到底是不是对的
This is diluting our ability to accurately predict the child's height,
基于我们了解的事实和数据
based on things that we actually know to be true and the data.
填充缺失值 削弱了我们模型的预测能力
For both imputing and removing missing values,
不论是删除缺失值还是填充缺失值
you should be very cautious of the final impact this will have on your model.
都要非常小心 注意处理结果对模型造成的影响